<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>EDA on Desmond Choy&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/eda/</link>
    <description>Recent content in EDA on Desmond Choy&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/eda/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Spotify Genre Popularity Through Time</title>
      <link>/2020/01/spotify-genre-popularity-through-the-decades/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/spotify-genre-popularity-through-the-decades/</guid>
      <description>This dataset was taken from the very popular TidyTuesday github repo, and this was my attempt at having a go at visualization given my love for music and this was a Spotify dataset.
Datasets from TidyTuesday are usually cleaned (or at least there’ll be instructions/hints on what one should first start with), and I begin by importing the data and wrangling it slightly by labelling the decades.
In the spirit of “Perfect is the enemy of good”, this will be a short post aimed at answering just a couple of questions with EDA and visualization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oil and Gas Sector 2019 (Part II)</title>
      <link>/2019/12/oil-and-gas-sector-2019-part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/12/oil-and-gas-sector-2019-part-ii/</guid>
      <description>Continuing on from Part I of this analysis, we move on Part II.
Part I: Data Importing and Wrangling (Tidying)Part II: Exploratory Data Analysis and interpretation of resultsIf you wish to replicate my findings, the raw Bloomberg data is available at my github.
Disclaimer
All data that I have used in this presentation is obtained from Bloomberg and I do not own any of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oil and Gas Sector 2019 (Part I)</title>
      <link>/2019/12/oil-and-gas-sector-2019-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/12/oil-and-gas-sector-2019-part-i/</guid>
      <description>While preparing for an internal sector presentation, I decided to experiment with R to see if I could replicate the results generated by Bloomberg and customize it further to shed more insight. The learning curve was steep but, on hindsight, I benefitted tremendously from the following:
A great opportunity to practise all aspects of Data Science. From Importing, to Tidying, to Exploratory Data Analysis, to my first ever R Markdown document!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>