<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>machine learning on Desmond Choy&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in machine learning on Desmond Choy&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Coffee Quality With ML</title>
      <link>/2020/08/predicting-coffee-quality-with-ml.en-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/08/predicting-coffee-quality-with-ml.en-us/</guid>
      <description>A LASSO model, random forest model and an XGBoost model walks into a cafe&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scoring Visualization Goals with PCA and FIFA 20</title>
      <link>/2020/06/scoring-visualization-goals-with-pca-and-fifa-20.en-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/scoring-visualization-goals-with-pca-and-fifa-20.en-us/</guid>
      <description>I came across this interesting dataset on Kaggle related to the football simulation video game FIFA 20, with a very detailed breakdown of attributes of over 18,000 football players. It’s been a while since I’ve played a FIFA game, and an even longer time since I last worn my soccer boots, but this seemed like an excellent data set for some Exploratory Data Analysis. I also showcase ridgeline plots and network graphs with wrangled data, and take a stab at implementing and interpreting unsupervised machine learning in the form of Principal Components Analysis on our wide data set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hip-Hop Lyrics Be Flowing with Tidy Text Mining</title>
      <link>/2020/05/hip-hop-lyrics-be-flowin-with-tidy-text-mining/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/hip-hop-lyrics-be-flowin-with-tidy-text-mining/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been hit with a double dose of NLP inspiration after reading a recent Julia Silge blog post and watching a Datacamp video on Tidy Text Mining which she used to teach. Ergo, this post will set out to do two things: use sentiment analysis to explore hip-hop songs, and subsequently use the tidymodels package on the lyrics to predict which era (Old School versus Modern) the songs came from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food Consumption and CO2 Emissions</title>
      <link>/2020/04/food-consumption-and-co2-emissions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/04/food-consumption-and-co2-emissions/</guid>
      <description>This will be my first attempt at machine learning using the tidymodels package, with a dataset taken from TidyTuesday. The code used to scrape this data can be found here.
The study analyses data from the Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO) to determine the quantity of produce supplied for consumption of 11 food types for all countries researched. Using CO2 emissions data, the carbon footprint per capita is then calculated for each food type.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>