<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NLP on Desmond Choy&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/nlp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in NLP on Desmond Choy&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/nlp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Your Vote Count By Counting Sentences</title>
      <link>/2020/07/make-your-vote-count-by-counting-sentences.en-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/make-your-vote-count-by-counting-sentences.en-us/</guid>
      <description>Singapore political manifestos are categorized using NLP. The results are fed into an interactive html table that allows for convenient sorting and filtering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Share Prices and Sentiment</title>
      <link>/2020/05/exploring-share-prices-and-sentiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/exploring-share-prices-and-sentiment/</guid>
      <description>Despite these troubling times brought upon us by Covid-19, one interesting investment theme has outperformed the market - “stay-at-home” stocks. These generally consist of companies that would benefit from the lockdown such as big retailers with delivery services, tech companies providing essential software for WFH setups, and video gaming companies that benefit from bored kids and adults. These companies have outperformed the broader indices significantly and, intuitively, sentiment for these companies should be positive, right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hip-Hop Lyrics Be Flowing with Tidy Text Mining</title>
      <link>/2020/05/hip-hop-lyrics-be-flowin-with-tidy-text-mining/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/hip-hop-lyrics-be-flowin-with-tidy-text-mining/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been hit with a double dose of NLP inspiration after reading a recent Julia Silge blog post and watching a Datacamp video on Tidy Text Mining which she used to teach. Ergo, this post will set out to do two things: use sentiment analysis to explore hip-hop songs, and subsequently use the tidymodels package on the lyrics to predict which era (Old School versus Modern) the songs came from.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>